<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on EcoDynamics | Sebastian Block</title>
    <link>https://blockecology.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on EcoDynamics | Sebastian Block</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blockecology.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Dynamics in Warmer Mountains</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/project/warmer-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/project/warmer-mountains/</guid>
      <description>Many of the most dramatic biological impacts of climate change are mediated by species interactions. Still, we largely ignore how climate change influences the way species interact, and how this affects community dynamics. Due to their steep climatic and ecologic gradients, mountains are excellent systems to study how species interactions will influence community dynamics in future climates.
For the main component of my doctoral research, in collaboration with Loic Pellisier, and Jake Alexander, we transplanted alpine communities to lower elevations in the Swiss Alps to investigate how species interactions depend on temperature and how novel competitors from lower elevations will impact alpine vegetation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitor Adaptation and Climate Change Responses</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/project/cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/project/cache/</guid>
      <description>The contrasting competitive environments that populations of a species face across their range can create mosaics of local adaptation. Locally adapted populations may differ in their responses to climate change when the traits selected by their new environment are correlated with those selected by the historical competitive environment.
I will test these ideas using a combination of greenhouse experiments and mathematical models.
In a first greenhouse experiment, I will estimate the relative fecundity of 15 genotypes of Arabidopsis thaliana when growing in competition with different species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fossil hunting with statistical models</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/project/fossils/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/project/fossils/</guid>
      <description>Fossils are exceptionally valuable for our understanding of the history of life. They are also extremely rare and difficult to find. For my M.Sc. thesis, I combined climate-envelope, taphonomy, and discovery models to identify potential fossil areas of Late Pleistocene Australian megafauna.
The idea is that for a place to have fossils of a given species, the species must have lived there before dying and becoming fossilized. Thus, by modeling the potential distribution of the species based on paleoclimate and fossil presence data, we can get a first idea of where to look for its fossils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest diversity and landscape heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/project/tepoz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/project/tepoz/</guid>
      <description>For the last 20 million years, volcanic activity in south-central Mexico has created a geological mosaic that shapes the patterns of structure and diversity of the vegetation across the region. In El Tepozteco National Park, just a few miles south of Mexico City, oak forests cover a complex geomorphological landscape composed of eroded lahars and lava flows of different ages and degrees of soil development.
For my Bachelor research thesis, I described the patterns of oak forest diversity and structure across this geomorphological mosaic, analysed its relation to landscape-scale environmental heterogeneity, and studied the potential of analysing Google Earth satellite image attributes to model and predict vegetation properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>