<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on EcoDynamics | Sebastian Block</title>
    <link>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on EcoDynamics | Sebastian Block</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blockecology.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Landscape-scale effects of geomorphological heterogeneity on variability of oak forest structure and composition in a monogenetic volcanic field</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-ped/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-ped/</guid>
      <description>Background: Eruptive events in monogenetic volcanic fields create mosaics of lava fields that result in different successional times and stages, and environmental conditions. Such geomorphological heterogeneity may be related to patterns of vegetation structure, diversity, and composition across a landscape.
Aims: To examine landscape-scale effects of geomorphological heterogeneity on the spatial variability of oak forest structure and composition in a monogenetic volcanic field.
Methods: We sampled oak forests in six geomorphological units within a monogenetic volcanic field in El Tepozteco National Park and carried out redundancy analyses to relate environmental variables to forest composition and structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Earth Surface Metrics to Predict Plant Species Richness in a Complex Landscape</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-remotesensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-remotesensing/</guid>
      <description>Google Earth provides a freely available, global mosaic of high-resolution imagery from different sensors that has become popular in environmental and ecological studies. However, such imagery lacks the near-infrared band often used in studying vegetation, thus its potential for estimating vegetation properties remains unclear. In this study, we assess the potential of Google Earth imagery to describe and predict vegetation attributes. Further, we compare it to the potential of SPOT imagery, which has additional spectral information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where to dig for fossils: Combining climate-envelope, taphonomy and discovery models</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/fossil-hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/fossil-hunting/</guid>
      <description>Fossils represent invaluable data to reconstruct the past history of life, yet fossil-rich sites are often rare and difficult to find. The traditional fossil-hunting approach focuses on small areas and has not yet taken advantage of modelling techniques commonly used in ecology to account for an organism?s past distributions. We propose a new method to assist finding fossils at continental scales based on modelling the past distribution of species, the geological suitability of fossil preservation and the likelihood of fossil discovery in the field, and apply it to several genera of Australian megafauna that went extinct in the Late Quaternary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structure and diversity of oak forests in El Tepozteco National Park (Morelos, Mexico)</title>
      <link>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-oakforests/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blockecology.github.io/publication/tepoz-oakforests/</guid>
      <description>Quercus (oak) is among the most speciose and widespread genera occurring in Mexico; paradoxically, the ecological knowledge about Mexican oak forests is meager. Here we describe the floristic composition, diversity, and structure of the terrestrial component of the oak forests of El Tepozteco National Park (TNP), Central Mexico, and relate their floristic and structural heterogeneity to the geomorphological complexity of the park. We randomly distributed sixty 100-$m^2$ plots among six geomorphological units: the lava fields of the Chichinautzin, Suchiooc, Otates (upper and lower) and Oclayuca volcanoes, and the El Tepozteco Range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>